westarenergy.com 2018-12-29

# Westar Energy, Inc. privacy policy

### Westar Energy, Inc. privacy policy

Policy revised: Aug. 27, 2015

Westar Energy, Inc. is committed to safeguarding your privacy on its Web sites located at www.westarenergy.com.  This Westar Energy Privacy Policy does not apply to products or services provided, or information obtained, other than through Westar Energy Web sites.  Please read the following policy to understand how your information will be treated.  Westar Energy may modify this policy from time to time by posting a revised policy at this Web site address, so please check back periodically.  When this policy is modified, if the modifications are significant, we will display the following next to the link to the policy at the Web sites: "[RECENTLY REVISED]", for a period of thirty (30) days following the posting.  Please keep in mind that some of the services mentioned specifically in this policy may not be available on our sites at this time.  If you have questions concerning this policy, please contact Westar Energy at [corpcomm@westarenergy.com](mailto:corpcomm@westarenergy.com).  The Westar Energy Web sites are not for use by children under the age of 13. 

##### What information does Westar Energy collect from me?

Westar Energy collects the following categories of personally identifiable information through the Web sites: your Westar Energy account number and password, and your email address.  In order to receive certain services, it is possible that we would request your name, postal address, phone number, Social Security number, bank account information, and date of birth.  Westar Energy collects information in several ways.  For example, some of this personal information is gathered when you register as a customer using our Account Interface.  During registration, we ask for your Westar Energy Account Number and your email address.  Once you register, you are no longer anonymous to Westar Energy and are able to take full advantage of our services.  In addition to registration, we may ask you for information at other times, such as when you report a problem with our sites or services, or contact the company via the corporate email address.  You may also transmit an email to us with your questions or comments.  If you contact Westar Energy, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

If you believe that any inaccurate or inappropriate information has been obtained or disseminated through your use of our Web sites, you should contact a representative of Westar Energy at [corpcomm@westarenergy.com](mailto:corpcomm@westarenergy.com).

#####  What are cookies and how does Westar Energy use them?

As part of offering and providing customizable and personalized services, many Web sites use cookies to store and sometimes track information about you.  A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer's hard drive.  We use cookies to allow faster and easier access to your account information, monitor traffic on our sites and measure traffic patterns to improve functionality.  Westar Energy Web pages may contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called clear gifs or Web bugs), log files, or other advanced technologies that are useful in the provision of services to you.

#####  How does Westar Energy use the information?

Westar Energy’s primary goal in collecting information is to improve the sites and provide the user with the best possible experience on the sites.  For example, by using the information collected, we are able to provide you with an easy to use and readily available forum to access your Westar Energy account information.  We will also use your personal information to allow you to pay your Westar Energy bills online, to send electronic notices to you, and to notify you of other products or services available from Westar Energy and its affiliates.  We may also use your information to enable certain approved companies who may partner with Westar Energy to provide you with the opportunity to obtain their services or products such as programmable thermostats, home electrical repair service plans; one-stop resource for connecting, moving, or stopping all utility services; home automation and security services, and other services or products directly or indirectly related to electric utility services.

We also may do research on our users' demographics and behavior based on the information provided to us upon registration, gathered from transaction activity, from our server log files or from surveys.  This research may be compiled, analyzed, or sold on an aggregated basis, which does not include information identifying individual users.  Westar Energy also may share this aggregated data with business partners or other third parties.

#####  Who is collecting information?

When you are on a Westar Energy site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with Westar Energy and its affiliates and service providers, including those approved business partners of Westar Energy who may offer you services.  If personal data is to be collected and/or maintained by any company other than Westar Energy or its affiliates and service providers, we will attempt to notify you on the Web site or in an updated version of this Privacy Policy.  If you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer by not using that particular service.

Please be aware that other Web sites to which we link may collect personally identifiable information about you when you visit those sites.  The information practices of other Web sites linked to www.westarenergy.com are not covered by this Privacy Policy. The website permits you to use a third party social networking platform such as Facebook, Twitter, and YouTube.  Generally, these icons point to our Westar Energy pages on each service.  When you use social networking platforms and plugins, you share your information with them and their privacy policy applies disclosure of such information.  In addition, they may be able to collect information about you, including your activity or may notify your connections on the social networking platform about your use of our websites.  Such services may allow your activity to be monitored across multiple websites for purposes of delivering more targeted advertising.  Please note that their own privacy polices apply and we encourage you to read them.  We may add new social networking plugins and buttons to our websites from time to time.

#####  Collection of non-personally identifying site traffic information

When you visit our website to read pages or download information, our web server logs automatically collect and store the following non-identifying information: the Internet protocol (IP) address from which you access our website, the type of browser and operating system used to access our site, the date and time our site is accessed, the pages visited and the last site you visited before arriving at our site.  We also use Google Analytics™ web analytics service to track additional non-identifying information (such as keywords used in searches to find our site, which pages are visited on our site, how long pages are viewed, etc.).

#####  With whom does Westar Energy share my information?  

We will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your permission, or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it, or under the circumstances described below.  The following describes some of the ways that your information may be disclosed.

Categories of Third Parties with whom Westar Energy may share personally identifiable information:  Westar Energy Service Providers:  Westar Energy may provide your personally identifiable information to its affiliates, and its trusted business partners or persons for the sole purpose of processing that information on behalf of Westar Energy.  When this is done, it is subject to commitments on the part of those parties to process such information only in accordance with Westar Energy's instructions, and to maintain appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

Third Party Service Providers:  Westar Energy may provide your personally identifiable information to enable certain approved companies to provide you with the opportunity to obtain their services such as pre-paid electrical services, bill consolidation services, home automation and security services, and other services or products directly or indirectly related to electric utility services.  

Data in the Aggregate: We may disclose “blinded” aggregated data and user statistics to prospective partners and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes.  Blinded data is data that does not identify an individual person.

Knowledge Base Information: We may post relevant questions that you ask in our Knowledge Base or Frequently Ask Questions sections of our Site.  We will not disclose your name in any such postings.

Other: We also may disclose account information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating Westar Energy Terms and Conditions of Use, or may otherwise be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) Westar Energy rights or property, other Westar Energy Web site users or customers, or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities. We may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain, service and improve our products and services.

We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, including packaging and mailing, answering customer questions about products or services, sending postal mail, providing investor information and processing data.  We will only provide those companies the information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

As we continue to develop our business, we may buy or sell businesses or assets.  In such transactions, confidential customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets.  In the event of a transaction involving the sale of some or all of Westar Energy businesses, customer and site visitor information may be one of the transferred assets.

##### How does Westar Energy protect financial-related information?

Keeping your personal financial information private is vitally important to us.  As a matter of policy and long-time business practice, Westar Energy does not sell information provided by our customers.  Any user statistics that we may provide to prospective partners regarding financial matters are provided in the aggregate only and do not include any personally identifiable information about any individual user.  We will transfer your bank account number or other personal information to the appropriate financial institution in order to process any online payments of your Westar Energy Customer Account.

##### What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?

Your personal and account information are password-protected so you have access to this personal information.  We use SSL (Secure Socket Layering) encryption technology for secure pages on our web sites, which can be identified by the letters “https:” at the beginning of the URL in the address field of your Internet browser.  Remember to sign out of your Westar Energy account and close your browser window when you have finished your work.  This is to ensure that others cannot access your account by using your computer when you are away from it.  Because of the global nature of the Internet, when you give us information, that information may be sent electronically to servers outside the country where you originally entered the information.  Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  Except as discussed above or otherwise designated, our sites do not use security encryption measures.  Therefore, information that you disclose by use of our sites (as with any site that is non-secure), by posting a message or using email, potentially could be collected and used by others.  This may result in unsolicited messages from third parties or use of such information by third parties for their own purposes, legal or illegal.  As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Westar Energy cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our services, and you do so at your own risk.  Once we receive your transmission, we use our best efforts to ensure its security on our systems.

##### What else should I know about my privacy?

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose information online, that information is accessible to other customers and users.  Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information.  Please be careful and responsible whenever you are online.

When you or we end your customer relationship with us, we will treat the information we have about you as if you were still our customer.

##### Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits our visitors who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes.  To make such a request, please send an email to or write us: [corpcomm@westarenergy.com](mailto:corpcomm@westarenergy.com) by email or you may contact us via regular mail at:

Westar Energy, Inc., Customer Programs and Services Dept., 818 S. Kansas Ave., Topeka, KS  66614

Make sure to state that you are a California Resident.

Do Not Track (DNT) is a privacy preference that users can set in their web browsers.  While the United States Federal Trade Commission has endorsed DNT, our website does not support DNT codes.  However, except in the case of analytics cookies, remarketing and other features of Google Display Advertising described above, our website limits tracking to the internal uses described above.  Except in the case of analytics cookies, remarketing and other features of Google Display Advertising described above, our website does not track your use across multiple websites, however, other websites to which we link may. Please review their privacy policies to understand how you may be tracked.
